

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate Analyst with an out-of-the-box mindset and hunger for growth. My career interests and experience are primarily focused on macroeconomics, corporate finance, quantitative finance and financial research. I am committed to unlocking as much value as possible across emerging markets and developing markets in Africa. I'm also an avid fan of sports, socialising and travel in my spare

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of birth 21/07/1994

Nationality

Namibian

Marital status Single

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

AFRIKAANS

WEBSITES & SOCIAL LINKS

eni-shatiwa-516040150/

Linkedin:

Website: https://tangenishatiwa.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tang

Github:

https://github.com/tanga94

REFERENCES **BENJAMIN BIWA**

Ariya Capital **T:** +264 61 256 795

E: ben@ariya.com.na

HYLTON HOLLANDER Stellenbosch University T: +27 21 808 2278

E: hylton@sun.ac.za

TANGENI SHATIWA

ECONOMIC ANALYST

- Windhoek, 9000, Namibia
 - +264818068801 / +27722575894

WORK EXPERIENCE

CENTRAL BANK OF NAMIBIA Windhoek

Jan 2020 - Present

Economic Analyst

- Maintained datasets and constructed quantitative models for inflation & financial reserves forecasting.
- Compiled the global and regional overview sections required for the bi-annual Economic Outlook reports.
- Assisted with decomposing quarterly financial account statistics (FDI, Portfolio Investment, Financial Derivatives) into instrument types & sectors. • Completed research on commodity markets
- required for MPC presentations (Crude Oil, Mining and Metals, Wheat and Maize).

• Performed in-depth financial and operational

Windhoek Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

IJG CAPITAL

screening on client companies. Analyzed market trends, competition, and potential strategic partners. • Conducted financial analysis on prospective M&A

Business Analyst Intern (Private Equity)

- companies using discounted cash flow, precedent transactions and comparable companies analyses • Prepared presentations on sector research within
- renewable energy market across Sub-Saharan Africa & healthcare market in Namibia.
- Assisted with the strategy formulation tailored at improving one of the portfolio company's working capital, which avoided its liquidation.

Windhoek Dec 2017 - May 2018

ARIYA CAPITAL

 Carried out sector research to source prospective M&A deals for the Fund (Renewable energy, Bulk

buyout methodologies.

Investment Analyst (Private Equity)

- infrastructure, Telecommunications, Water & Sanitation). • Performed financial valuation analysis through the use of discounted cash flow, trading comparables,
 - Compiled reports required to be submitted to Namibian regulatory authorities (NAMFISA and

precedent transaction comparables, and leveraged

- Presented the investment pipeline to the African Development Bank which resulted in the Fund's size increasing by \$30 Million.

Cape Town Jan 2014 - Oct 2015

BIG MERCHANDISE

EVENTS COMPANY

in the Cape Town area.

Sales Representative

• Managed cash and inventory levels at the

• Part time merchandise sales work at major concerts

- merchandise sales desk. • Responded to customer requests and complaints,
- as well as handled customer requests. • Created promotional strategies and calendars to
 - grow merchandise sales by 10% in 2015.

CFA INSTITUTE

EDUCATION

2020 **STELLENBOSCH**

New York

UNIVERSITY Stellenbosch, Western Cape 2019

CFA Level 1

Masters Degree - Financial Economics

Microeconomics and Macroeconomics, Advanced Macroeconomic Policy, International Finance, Economics of Tech Change, Time Series Econometrics, Development Economics) • Thesis - Decomposing the Heterogeneity in

• Coursework (Applied Finance, Applied

Portfolio Flows to Emerging Markets (Grade - 76%) Final GPA - 70% (3.2 GPA)

Achievements and Societies - Full Scholarship

- (Central Bank of Namibia), Volunteering (English and Math Tutoring in Kayamandi), Monetary Policy
- Research Team (SU), Investment Society, Namibian Society Bachelors (Honours) Degree - Economics • Majors - Finance (Capital Investments, Mergers and

Acquisitions, Financial Research) and Economics

HIGH SCHOOL (SACS)

Stellenbosch, Western Cape

STELLENBOSCH

UNIVERSITY

2017

SOUTH AFRICAN COLLEGE •

Cape Town, Western Cape 2012

• Achievements and Societies - Half Scholarship

(Microeconomics, Macroeconomics)

- Award (Rugby), 1st Team Rugby Representative, u21 Rugby Captain, Residence Sporting Excellence Award (2014), Landmark Award for Leadership, Investment Society, Namibian Society
- **Higher National Certificate** • GPA - 80% (3.7 GPA) • Achievements - Full Colours (Basketball, Rugby,

SKILLS

Academics), Ludwig Award (1st in Class for Economics and Accounting), Tutor Prefect, Sprit Committee Team Leader, Orators Award (Debating)

BLOOMBERG TERMINAL

EVIEWS GITHUB FINANCIAL MODELLING (DCF AND LBO) **ECONOMETRIC MODELLING** FINANCIAL RESEARCH **EQUITY ANALYSIS** COMMUNICATION, STRATEGY, PROFESSIONALISM AND TEAMWORK

Mar 2020

COURSES

Apr 2020

Jan 2020

Jan 2018

HOBBIES SPORTS, RUNNING, WINE TASTING, TRAVEL, INTERNATIONAL MARKETS AND **POLITICS**

Teaching English Language to Foreigners, TEFL Master

Complete Financial Analyst Course, Udemy

Quantitative Finance with R, Udemy

Data Science and Machine Learning in R, Udemy

Academic Research Papers -

WEBSITE

(https://tangenishatiwa.netlify.app/publication/) • Decompising the heterogeneity in portfolio flows

to emerging markets using Stuctural VAR

- Assessing the co-movement in emerging market equity indices: Using Dynamic Conditional Correlations in the pre and post Lehman era under
- low and high VIX episodes • A Bayesian game-theoretic approach towards understanding the trade war between the US and China

An Overview on Renewable Energy Technology

OTHER JOBS HELD

Stellenbosch University Jan 2019 - Dec 2019

Tutor - TeachMe2

(RET) Diffusion Models

techniques

 Assisted 1st and 2nd year Finance and Economics students with assignments and exam preparation through TeachMe2, an Educational start-up in South Africa

Chiang Mai, Thailand May 2018 - Dec 2018

English Teacher - IGenius Language Centre

• I spent 8 months abroad in Thailand tutoring Business English to university students and adults